<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Re: boot</title><link>https://blog.eternalwings.de/</link><description>Recent content on Re: boot</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2025 10:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.eternalwings.de/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Silkroad Online Network Protocol - an introduction</title><link>https://blog.eternalwings.de/posts/2023-05-24-silkroad-packet-format/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2025 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://blog.eternalwings.de/posts/2023-05-24-silkroad-packet-format/</guid><description>&lt;p>This is a series of posts about Silkroad Online or, more specifically, about things I encounter when writing my &lt;a href="https://github.com/kumpelblase2/skrillax">skrillax&lt;/a> emulator for it. To lay the foundation making the later parts understandable, this introduction provides the basics of the network protocol used in Silkroad Online. None of this is really new information and is simply compiled to provide a self contained explanation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When designing a (network) protocol, there are a few things you want to strive for. One of the being avoiding ambiguity and another being consistency. You wouldn&amp;rsquo;t want a packet to be parsed differently, depending on the time of day. Or if you want to represent a concept, like a list of something, to be encoded in several different ways. This makes it significantly easier to parse and work with as it allows for a single, simple parsing pass and better reuse of code across different areas. In the following I want to look closer that the protocol used by &lt;a href="https://www.joymax.com/SilKRoaD/">Silkroad Online&lt;/a>, but first lets go over some basics.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Skrillax</title><link>https://blog.eternalwings.de/projects/skrillax/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.eternalwings.de/projects/skrillax/</guid><description>&lt;p>Rust seemed like a language worth exploring for me, as I wanted to have some more experience with &amp;ldquo;lower level&amp;rdquo; languages. My main languages so far had been Java and JavaScript/TypeScript, followed by only partial knowledge of many others. Almost all of them, however, were &amp;ldquo;high level&amp;rdquo; languages, i.e. are interpreted or run inside some bytecode VM. But because of all of these, I was accustomed to using generics, lambdas, and often had a big focus on type safety. When I tried C it really felt like I was treated like a toddler, who wasn&amp;rsquo;t yet allowed to play with the grown-up toys and instead had to be content with the few basic blocks they had. Go&amp;rsquo;s concurrency model was quite refreshing, but similarly felt incomplete due to having no generics at the time. Then there was Rust, the cool kid on the block now, having - on the surface - all of what I was looking for. Lots of resources too; blogs, videos, news. All within a similar-enough package to where a &amp;ldquo;hello world&amp;rdquo; was straight forward. But - obviously - a hello world is not enough to know a language.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Its Been a Long Time</title><link>https://blog.eternalwings.de/posts/2019-12-11-its-been-a-long-time/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2019 17:28:07 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.eternalwings.de/posts/2019-12-11-its-been-a-long-time/</guid><description>&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s been a long time since I&amp;rsquo;ve posted anything here, in fact it&amp;rsquo;s been more than four years. Actually, it&amp;rsquo;s almost exactly five years since I made the first post. So is it just a coincidence that I just now thought about writing again? Maybe, but I think the situation is a pretty similar to when I wrote that first post. The university semester was on its way to the winter break so lectures were a bit more relaxing, I started spending more time on programming projects again and I found myself in having a bit of free time to do stuff in.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>About</title><link>https://blog.eternalwings.de/about/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2019 17:19:14 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.eternalwings.de/about/</guid><description>&lt;p>Tim is my name. I&amp;rsquo;m currently doing my master in computer science and live in Germany. I mostly work with Java-based backend services, but do work up and down the stack. In my free time I work on different kinds of projects but generally some that make my life easier. Occasionally I like to play games and am interested in esports, IT-security and open source.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Seeker</title><link>https://blog.eternalwings.de/projects/twitch-browse/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.eternalwings.de/projects/twitch-browse/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://blog.eternalwings.de/seeker/">Live Version&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Seeker is a project I started recently which should help people find new streams on &lt;a href="https://twitch.tv">Twitch&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h1 id="the-idea">The Idea&lt;a href="#the-idea" class="anchor" aria-hidden="true">&lt;svg xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2000/svg" viewBox="0 0 24 24" fill="none" stroke="currentColor" stroke-width="2"
 stroke-linecap="round" stroke-linejoin="round">
 &lt;path d="M15 7h3a5 5 0 0 1 5 5 5 5 0 0 1-5 5h-3m-6 0H6a5 5 0 0 1-5-5 5 5 0 0 1 5-5h3">&lt;/path>
 &lt;line x1="8" y1="12" x2="16" y2="12">&lt;/line>
 &lt;/svg>&lt;/a>&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>While Twitch does have a page to browse for the streams with currently the most viewers to find new streams, I found that page to be rather inadequate for that purpose. The reason is that for most people (including me) when they&amp;rsquo;re searching for new stuff to watch, they don&amp;rsquo;t reall know exactly what they&amp;rsquo;re looking for. Instead, I know what I&amp;rsquo;m &lt;em>not&lt;/em> looking for. For example, you can see this in the British parlament when they&amp;rsquo;re talking about Brexit. Jokes aside, I think this is a general problem that doesn&amp;rsquo;t only apply to finding a new streamer, but for any case where you have a lot of choices without any clear constraints (another example might be window shopping). You could go on and look through the whole page of streams, but why wouldn&amp;rsquo;t Twitch allow you to remove certain streams that &lt;em>you know&lt;/em> you won&amp;rsquo;t watch?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Vima</title><link>https://blog.eternalwings.de/projects/vima/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.eternalwings.de/projects/vima/</guid><description>&lt;p>I have a big collection of videos that aren&amp;rsquo;t movies or series (educational videos for example) which I&amp;rsquo;d like to organize so I can search for specific ones, track progress or make notes. Sadly, the only kind of software that is in this space are &amp;ldquo;Media Servers&amp;rdquo;. I say &amp;ldquo;sadly&amp;rdquo; because those media servers are made for movies and tv shows where there&amp;rsquo;s public metadata available that a server can provide in addition to streaming the video itself. However, for videos that aren&amp;rsquo;t movies or shows, this rarely exists or isn&amp;rsquo;t easily queryable. Because I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find a software that satisfied my requirements, I started working on Vima.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Proxtop</title><link>https://blog.eternalwings.de/projects/proxtop/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.eternalwings.de/projects/proxtop/</guid><description>&lt;p>Repository: &lt;a href="https://github.com/kumpelblase2/proxtop">Here&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kumpelblase2/proxtop/master/static/assets/proxtop_logo_256.png" alt="Proxtop Logo">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Proxtop evolved out of my desire to be notified of new anime episodes being available instead of manually having to check for new releases by going to the website. I had already done some small server side scripts that did this for me, but I thought that if I wanted to make this available to other people, a server application isn&amp;rsquo;t gonna cut it. You can see that project &lt;a href="https://github.com/kumpelblase2/proxer-watchlist-push">here&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The only reason I can't love linux</title><link>https://blog.eternalwings.de/posts/2015-03-27-the-only-reason-i-cant-love-linux/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2015 14:04:31 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.eternalwings.de/posts/2015-03-27-the-only-reason-i-cant-love-linux/</guid><description>&lt;p>Let me get this straight first, I really like Linux. It&amp;rsquo;s pretty much everything I love about OSX just wrapped up in a more customizable, easier accessible and more diverse operating system. But there&amp;rsquo;s one thing, which is a showstopper for me.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There&amp;rsquo;s on thing I have used since my windows days and continue to use it to this very day on OSX. It&amp;rsquo;s Little Snitch (on Windows it was Zone Alarm). It&amp;rsquo;s the application that I will install first on any new Mac that I&amp;rsquo;d get and I will not be using a computer productively without it. Why? That&amp;rsquo;s quite simple. I want control over what applications can do and can&amp;rsquo;t do while still being able to use the rest of the application without further issues. That&amp;rsquo;s why I prefer iOS over Android as well, as I can deny for example the access to my contacts but don&amp;rsquo;t get locked out of the app completely like I&amp;rsquo;d get in android (where I can either allow everything and install it or just can&amp;rsquo;t even download it). This is the only reasonable behavior to me, why should and app no longer work if I deny only parts of what it needs? Right, I won&amp;rsquo;t be able to use that specific part of the app but I mean, if I block that specific part I have my reasons to not use that feature anyway. For an app to say &amp;ldquo;Sorry, I can&amp;rsquo;t work at all if you don&amp;rsquo;t allow this&amp;rdquo; it really has to be the core feature of it. And for that case, I&amp;rsquo;d be happy to search for a similar app that doesn&amp;rsquo;t necessary require that feature. The same thing applies to network connections. Sometimes it&amp;rsquo;s enough to say &amp;ldquo;You are not allowed to access the internet at all&amp;rdquo; for certain applications like simple editors or other offline applications, but that&amp;rsquo;s not often the case. For example, what about updates? The app should be able to check for those, but here&amp;rsquo;s the catch, ONLY for those. Why should the app be able to connect to isenddatasomewhere.com for updates as well, because it&amp;rsquo;s surely not the right domain to check for updates. However, I might want to allow it for some other application to connect to that domain.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The world we live in</title><link>https://blog.eternalwings.de/posts/2015-03-18-the-world-we-live-in/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Mar 2015 22:03:50 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.eternalwings.de/posts/2015-03-18-the-world-we-live-in/</guid><description>&lt;p>Sometimes I wonder, what do people write about? Todays events? Discussion topics? Crazy stories that no one would ever believe? I don&amp;rsquo;t feel like writing about such things. Because the world we live in is crazy enough already. Just think about it, how many of our own planet we have yet to discover. What kind of animals have lived on this planet to this very day and how many will live for long after. The is so much to discover even just on the planet we all live on. So what if take a look at things a bit further away, like the moon. Have we discovered everything about it yet? We might, we might not.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>I Just Feel Like Writing About This</title><link>https://blog.eternalwings.de/posts/2015-01-16-i-just-feel-like-writing-about-this/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2015 13:02:34 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.eternalwings.de/posts/2015-01-16-i-just-feel-like-writing-about-this/</guid><description>&lt;p>The title doesn&amp;rsquo;t really give anything away about the content, so what is it about? So I watched a TED talk the other day from Susan Cain, &amp;ldquo;The power of introverts&amp;rdquo;, and she also touches the topic about introverts in school. I just want to give my experience on this topic, not about introverts in school, but in university.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I would consider myself an introvert right now, however, when I was younger I wasn&amp;rsquo;t as introverted as I currently am. This was especially true in the first years of my secondary education, however, it started to shift as soon as I got into programming. Earlier, I was completely fine working in bigger groups and that pretty often. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t too common in school, but it happened every now and then. So it was all nice and dandy until that point. But what changed when I got into programming?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>GTA 5 Getting Pulled From the Shelves in Australia</title><link>https://blog.eternalwings.de/posts/2014-12-12-gta-5-getting-pulled-from-the-shelves-in-australia/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2014 12:56:36 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.eternalwings.de/posts/2014-12-12-gta-5-getting-pulled-from-the-shelves-in-australia/</guid><description>&lt;p>&amp;ndash; Disclaimer
There are a lot of posts about this on the internet already, spanning from well written ones to ones that try to defend the opinion with empty statements. This will be nothing more than a rant about what some peoples opinions are and generally my own one on the topic. You are free to agree and/or disagree with me or even critizise me in this regard, but be warned that I won&amp;rsquo;t get into a discussion with you in anyway about this topic. It is possible that I might bring up the same argument as other people, but that&amp;rsquo;s just the nature of rants. Also, this may contain mature content and heavy outrage, so take this into consideration before reading on. &lt;br>
&amp;ndash; Disclaimer end&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>What Is This?</title><link>https://blog.eternalwings.de/posts/2014-12-11-what-is-this/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2014 10:42:34 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.eternalwings.de/posts/2014-12-11-what-is-this/</guid><description>&lt;p>This is, as you might&amp;rsquo;ve noticed, something that looks like a blog, doesn&amp;rsquo;t it? Well, it is indeed some form of blog, but don&amp;rsquo;t expect it to have (continuously) new content on it. I tend to forget such things pretty easily and then I found something new and get rid of the old stuff&amp;hellip; Which might be somewhat sad but I just like to try out all the new things.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>